I've been using the rep Fitness Helios
squat bar over the past month and my
three favorite things about it are the
thicker diameter which leads to less
flexion under heavy loads it's fully
knurled so it's going to really allow
you to get the maximum grip between your
back and the bar and the cerakote Finish
offers a really high level of protection
against rust and corrosion if you're
looking to hit a new squat PR you might
have just found your new best friend
let's get asked
[Music]
I don't know
what's up y'all it's Jake back in the
barbing garage gym and this time around
we've got the rep Fitness Helios squat
bar info review I'm going to talk about
a lot today but specifically we're going
to talk about some money some pros and
cons and who should or maybe should not
add this barbell to their home gym but
before I do all that gotta let you know
we've reviewed a lot of barbells on
barbin.com and we went ahead and came up
with the best list of all of our top
choices so if you want to check that out
all you got to do is search bar bed best
barbells it's going to pull right up for
you and you might be surprised which one
cracks the number one spot
okay
[Music]
okay so let's talk about some pros and
cons I've noticed while I've been
training with this bar and I think the
first thing I want to talk about is the
thickness all right so this bar is 32
millimeters in diameter with your
traditional power bar they're 28 and a
half 29 millimeters so that extra
thickness you know it makes the bar more
rigid especially under heavy loads
you're going to have less flexion and
speaking of heavy loads these loading
sleeves are 17 inches long I mean it's
I'm sure this bar is almost coming out
of the frame right here so that extra
length on your loading sleeves is really
going to allow you to pack on the weight
plates so if you're somebody who's you
know upper echelon in terms of strength
I think you're really going to like that
I also really like how this is a fully
knurled barbell now it's going to create
you know the most traction most grip
possible between your back and the bar
which is a really good thing and then
also really like how there's this Center
ring right here it's going to allow you
to you know evenly you know Step Up
underneath the bar and be right in the
middle it's going to be a really cool
thing too and also I really like how it
is a cerakote finish it's going to offer
that really high level of protection now
with those cons I mean I think the first
thing we got to talk about is the lack
of Versatility you know this is strictly
you know for squatting it says it in the
name Helios squat bar and it's 400 bucks
so while some people might find that
justifiable also understand why some
people won't because
and you can spend that much money on
another barbell and be way more
versatile when you can hit all of your
lifts with it and then really the only
other thing here is that it's not
stainless steel you know cerakote like I
said offers a high level of protection
from rust and corrosion but it's still
number two to stainless steel so for
somebody you know who prioritizes their
barbells being stainless steel I get it
you can probably go find yourself
another option out there
[Music]
okay so once again the rep Fitness Helio
squat bar is listed right around 400
bucks now I think it's worthy of that
price tag because of the high quality
that it is but I totally understand why
somebody wouldn't want to spend 400 on a
squat specific barbell that said it's
still cheaper than the Rogue 32
millimeter squat bar and it's cheaper
than the coated options of the Texas
squat bar so if you are in fact looking
for a squat specific barbell I think
this is one of your best options now
another bar that I really like is also
from rep Fitness it's the Double Black
Diamond it's going to cost you about 330
bucks and it's a true power bar so in
addition to squatty you can also do you
know your benching and your dead lifting
and shoulder press all that stuff now
you could find a way to you know do that
still there's other lifts still with
this bar but it's not meant for that so
if you're not looking you know just for
a squat specific bar and you do want a
power bar maybe you want to check that
one out foreign
okay so this is a 25 kilogram bar which
is about 55 pounds so it's you know
roughly 10 11 pounds heavier than your
standard 20 kilogram bar and the reason
for that is because it's thicker right
so remember the shaft right here is 32
millimeters as opposed to your standard
you know 28 28 and a half 29 whatever
because of that extra thickness you know
it's leading to a heavier bar because
there's more steel that is being used so
this is a cerakote coating right here on
the shaft but the sleeves are DuraCoat
so DuraCoat is a chemical process
basically that just makes that steel
right there more resilient you know more
tough so that's a good thing you know
but you might notice some you know
markings on the sleeves and that's
basically just you're pulling material
out from you know the inside of your
weight plates that's really all that it
is you can wipe the sleeves down and
it'll mostly go away just kind of keep
that in mind now you do have a pretty
aggressive Mountain style knurling right
here so each individual marking sticks
up as a mountain does now
this is great for a power bar but I also
love the fact that it's a fully knurled
barbell it's kind of rare and I like
that a lot you know it's gonna like I
said earlier it really you know
increases the amount of traction and
grip you're able to get between your
upper back or if you do low back squats
but your back and the bar and also I
really like how there's a center ring
right here just allows you to get
centered up perfectly as you go to get
underneath the barbell you do have
international powerlifting Federation
markings right here so that's nice too
now the loading sleeves do have bronze
bushings so I mean yes it spins a little
bit but not doing any type of you know
Olympic or CrossFit style lifts unless
your hands are you know tough as Nails
because this knurling right here is just
gonna rip you to shreds and also it's
just too long you wouldn't really like
that speaking of length this bar is 94
inches long with 17 inch loading sleeves
so as I mentioned earlier you know that
extra length on the loading sleeves is
going to really allow you to pack on
those weight plates if you're somebody
who's squatting some IP hopping weight
it does have a 1500 pound weight
capacity which is pretty much the market
Standard nowadays and it has a tensile
strength rating of 200 000 PSI so
tensile strength is just going to tell
you it's that number is going to tell
you how strong a barbell is and kind of
how much force and everything it can
withstand before it begins to bend on
you and lose its you know original shape
200 000 is really respectable you know
this spectrum of tinsel strength ranges
from 150 to up to 230 000 something 235
000 PSI barbells but 200 000 that is
right in that sweet spot and it's you
know perfect for the pretty much every
single lifter
[Music]
foreign
remember with this barbell your loading
sleeves are 17 inches long so that's
about 0.7 to around an inch longer than
your standard barbell so you're gonna be
able to pack on some more weight and if
you're somebody who's using you know
thin steel competition plates you're
really going to be able to pack on even
more weight so that's really nice
remember this is DuraCoat right here so
I don't know if you can tell but as you
you know put your plates on and you know
pull them off you're going to notice
some ridges not even ridges but you're
gonna notice some lines markings in your
sleeve right here it's not causing
damage to the to the Loading sleeve
trust me you can take a rag and kind of
wipe it off and it'll come off for the
most part now as I move further on I
really like how thick this you know
shaft is right here 32 millimeters in
diameter remember as I mentioned earlier
your standard power bar is about 29
millimeters so that's going to be really
nice you know it adds to the stiffness
of the bar which is something that you
definitely want when you're squatting I
also really enjoy first of all I really
enjoy the knurling in general you know
this sharp Mountain knurling it really
just gets the job done for me and it's
not too aggressive to where it it hurts
to you know get underneath the bar it's
definitely the case with some bars
mainly the bare steel ones but that's
not the case here which I really like
remember I talked about how you have
this Center ring right here to allow you
to get centered up under the bar but I
really like how there's full knurling
right here so typically with a power bar
you're only getting about maybe that
much knurling or so right here in the
middle and yeah that helps in terms of
keeping the bar on your back and getting
that extra grip but with it fully
knurled like that I mean my goodness
it's like
sticky tack you know it's just stuck to
my back when I'm lifting and that's
definitely something that you want so
while I personally think this is a
really high quality barbell and it's
great for squatting
I wouldn't recommend it for everybody so
if you're just now building out your
home gym and you're looking for
versatile products or maybe you're not
really in that top tier strength level
then no I really wouldn't recommend this
for you because it's not versatile you
know that being said though if you are
you know a hardcore dedicated squatter
you're looking to go up into that next
tier of squatting and you're looking for
a barbell to kind of walk hand in hand
with you and help you help you get there
then yeah I think this is perfect for
you you know it's got that extra
thickness so there's you know less
flexion under heavy loads I love the
fact that it's fully knurled so you know
if that's you if I'm describing you and
what you're looking for then yes this is
worth it but you know if not then I
probably spend your money elsewhere
foreign
[Music]
that's all I got for y'all today on the
rep Fitness Helios squat bar remember
you know this is a niche barbell and I
wouldn't necessarily recommend it for
everybody out there but if you do fall
within that target audience that this
bar was designed for I personally think
that you're gonna love it thanks for
watching y'all hope this video is really
helpful and I was able to break down all
the fine details you need to know about
this barbell as always stay posted for
my next video but for now head over to
barvin.com because we have a full
written article about this barbell that
I definitely think you should go and
check out all you gotta do is search bar
Bend rep Fitness Helios squat Bar review
it's going to pull right up for you you
can go over all the details and every
single thing we discussed here today now
it's time for some leg day action I'll
see y'all next time
[Music]
foreign